PRABIN B. LAMICHHANE

pblamichha42@tntech.edu

I am a Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science with five years of working experience in Network Security, Anomaly Detection, Machine Learning, Data Science, and Graph Mining. Currently, I am working on research related to anomaly/fraud detection in dynamic networks using graph-based techniques.

EDUCATION:

Tennessee Tech UniversityCookeville, TNPh.D. (Computer Science)2018 – Present

GPA: 4/4

Tennessee State UniversityNashville, TNM.S. (Computer and Information Sys. Engineering)2016 – 2018

GPA: 4/4

Tribhuvan UniversityKathmandu, NepalB.E. (Electronics & Computer Engineering)2011 – 2015

GPA: 3.72/4

EXPERIENCES:

Tennessee Tech UniversityCookeville, TNGraduate Teaching and Research Assistant2018 – Present

- Currently working on research related to anomaly/fraud detection in streaming (dynamic) networks such as Denial-of-Service attacks (DoS) in computer networks, social networks impersonations, or fake recommendations in e-commerce networks, etc. using graph-based techniques like probabilistic, embedding, and sketching.
- <u>Assisted Courses</u>: Data Structures and Algorithms, Discrete Structures for CSC, Foundation of CSC, Database Management Systems

Tennessee Tech University Internship (Research Assistant)

Cookeville, TN May 2018 – Aug 2018

• Formally analyzed the transmission scheduling process of the WirelessHART networks using Satisfiability Modulo Theories (SMT). That is, this research formally models the WirelessHART networks configuration and various constraints (like number of channels, and flow deadline) as inputs and verifies the schedulability of the packets under certain success specifications.

Tennessee State University Graduate Research Assistant

Nashville, TN 2016 – 2018

• Performed research on network security; finding a stepping stone path towards the node which has the highest impact on the network (i.e., the node whose exploitation causes the greatest loss on the organization). So that defenders can mitigate network attack problems by either changing any of the paths towards node or sifting node to the place where it will be more secure.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Language: Python, C, C++, MATLAB/Octave, SQL, LaTeX.

Software Tools: Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Tableau,

Weka, Git/Github, Jupyter Notebook, NPView, Nmap, OPNET, Wireshark, NS2, Network

Simulator.

Data Skill: Anomaly/Fraud Detection, Machine Learning, Data Mining, Data Visualization, Data

Cleaning, Graph Mining, Time-series Analysis.

Database: MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server.

PUBLICATIONS:

2022 P. B. Lamichhane, H. Mannering, W. Eberle, "Discovering Breach Patterns on the Internet

of Health Things: A Graph and Machine Learning Anomaly Analysis". The Florida Artificial

Intelligence Research Society (FLAIRS-35).

2022 R. Manicavasagam, **P. B. Lamichhane**, P. Kandel, D. Talbert, "Drug Repurposing for Rare

Orphan Diseases using Machine Learning Techniques". The Florida Artificial Intelligence

Research Society (FLAIRS-35).

2021 P. B. Lamichhane, W. Eberle, "Anomaly Detection in Edge Streams Using Term Frequency-

Inverse Graph Frequency (TF-IGF) Concept," 2021 IEEE International Conference on Big

Data (Big Data) 2021. pp. 661-667, doi: 10.1109/BigData52589.2021.9671424.

2018 P. B. Lamichhane, L. Hong and S. Shetty, "A Quantitative Risk Analysis Model and

Simulation of Enterprise Networks," 2018 IEEE 9th Annual Information Technology, Electronics and Mobile Communication Conference (IEMCON), 2018, pp. 844-850,

doi:10.1109/IEMCON.2018.8615080.

Under Review P. B. Lamichhane, W. Eberle, "Self-Organizing Map Based Graph Clustering and

Visualization on Streaming Graphs for Anomaly Detection". (Submitted to 28th ACM

SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD).

Under Process P. B. Lamichhane, W. Eberle, "Anomaly Detection in Graph Structured Data: A Survey"

(Target date: Early May, 2022)

PRESENTATIONS:

Research Paper Presentation, 2018 IEEE 9th Annual Information Technology, Electronics and Mobile Communication Conference (IEMCON), University of British Columbia, Canada.

Research Presentation, on "Anomaly Detection in Edge Streams Using Term Frequency-Inverse Graph Frequency (TF-IGF) Concept", at the Graduate Student Seminar, 2021.

Research Paper Presentation, 2021 IEEE International Conference on Big Data (IEEE BigData 2021), Orlando, Florida, USA.

RESEARCH INTERESTS:

- Graph-based Anomaly Detection
- Graph Embedding and Sketching
- Cyber Security Data Analysis
- Anomaly/ Fraud Detection
- Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence
- Network Security

CERTIFICATIONS:

- *Machine Learning*
- Applied Data Science with Python

Stanford University

University of Michigan